Let's get started with Day 1 for the month of October.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sarese.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
Welcome to a new month of Eikaiwa Time Trial.
今年度のテーマは英語でつながる船の旅。
毎月異なる国や地域をクルーズ船に乗って巡ります。
We're cruising the Atlantic.
That's right, everyone.
The next station is this one.
Ireland.
Ireland is located west of Great Britain, England.
And on Friday, this person will invite you to Ireland.
Hi, everyone. It's Nora.
I'll be your conversation partner around Ireland.
My hometown's in Ireland.
I grew up in a place called Bell Mullet.
Ireland has great food.
So, let's talk about food this month.
See you Friday.
Thanks, Nora.
Nora was born in Ireland.
Nora from Ireland will be your conversation partner.
And did you hear that?
She said, let's talk about food.
That's right.
私たちの学習テーマはこちら。
食や料理をテーマに学習してきます。
それではSPRトレーニングから始めましょう。
今回は料理の手順を英語で分かりやすく説明する表現を練習します。
一回目の挑戦に行きましょう。
どれぐらい言えるか力でメッシュしましょう。
It's time for your first try.
F.P.R. Training
Now, please try to express the Japanese I say in English within the time limit.
Boil the hot water and try to say it in English, please.
Now, before we move on to the next sentence, let's check the expression.
In English, 入れる.
I use it a lot in cooking.
What should I put in?
Please say it in English.
The answer is put in.
Then, let's use put in to say this.
Put in salt.
OK.
The next expression also uses put in.
Here.
Next, put in olive oil.
さあ、次はこの文です。
お湯が沸いています。
The water...
軽い言ってください。
どうぞ。
もう、麺を入れましょう。
Let's put in...
軽い言ってください。
どうぞ。
もう、麺を取り出しましょう。
さあ、次の文に行く前に、このフレーズを確認しましょう。
救う、ご飯やアイスクリームを救う。
英語で言うと、どうぞ。
The answer is scoop or scoop out.
スクープアウトが分かりやすいです。
では、スクープアウトを使ってこちらを言ってください。
ご飯をすくってください。
では続いて英語で乗せるっていうのは?
答えはput on。
ではput onを使ってこちらを言ってください。
それを海苔に乗せて。
ご飯を乗せすぎないでくださいね。
OK, how was your first round? Did you try to say each one?
では、ここで回答例をチェックしましょう。
Now you can check your answers with mine. Listen closely.
お湯を沸かして
Boil the water
一般的に命令文はソフトに言う必要があるので
just plus 動詞の原形が広く使えておすすめ
ただし、料理のレシピの説明など、手順について言うときは、
just も please もつけずに、動詞から始めるのが一般的。
ここで、boil the water。
一回、ジェニーさんの宛てに言ってみよう。
Boil the water.
さあ、次です。
塩を入れて。
Put in some salt.
何々を入れるを言うのに、put in。
そしてそのまま put in 目的語 some salt でも大丈夫ですし put some salt in と言っても正解です 言い慣れてる方で大丈夫です
では次です 次にオリーブオイルを入れて
Next put in some olive oil
お湯が沸いています
The water is boiling
Mō men o iremashou.
Let's put in the noodles now.
Mō men o tori dashimashou.
Let's take out the noodles now.
Ireru, put in, soshite dasu, tori dasu, take out.
Kantan ni ryōri no tejun o iemasu ne.
Sa, tsugi wa scoop out.
Kochira no bun desu.
Gohan o sukutte.
Scoop out some rice.
それを海苔にのせて。
Put it on the nori.
のりの英語は、
Seaweedよりもそのままのりを言うのがおすすめです。
Seaweedはあまり食欲をそそるような言い方ではないので、
そのままのり。
そしてその後相手に見せたり、
説明したりすればいいです。
では最後です。
ごはんをのせすぎないでくださいね。
Just don't put on too much rice.
相手と楽しく料理をしている場合は、
このようにjustを使って、
Just don't put on too much rice.
温かみのあるニュアンスになります。
OK, did you understand today's phrases?
それではみなさん、
今学習した表現をテンポよくもう一度言ってみましょう。
We'll pick up the pace a little in round two.
Here we go.
お湯を沸かして
Boil the water.
塩を入れて
Put in some salt.
次にオリーブオイルを入れて
Next, put in some olive oil.
お湯が沸いています。
The water is boiling.
もう麺を入れましょう。
Let's put in the noodles now.
もう麺を取り出しましょう。
Let's take out the noodles now.
ごはんをすくって。
Scoop out some rice.
それをのりにのせて。
Put it on the nori.
ごはんをのせすぎないでくださいね。
Just don't put on too much rice.
Okay, time's up.
How was your second try?
Did you do a little better than before?
さあ、今月はこういう基本的な言葉を使って
料理や食事について楽しく会話できるようになってきましょう。
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on Ekaewa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.